- Fire!
- Stand back!
Everyone go into the woods!
Fire!
Fall back!
- You okay?
- Come on, Bob. Bring him over that way.
- Captain, you all right?
- Get down!
- Gatling! They got a Gatling!
- Goddamn it, Cole!
This stopped being fun
about two years ago!
Move that wagon!
- Down!
- Fire!
- Cole, Bob, you boys okay?
- Yeah.
Take more than a cannon to kill
the Younger brothers, sir!
I think the cannon's doing
a pretty good job, Cole!
Some Indian tracker
ou turned out to be, Tom.
You paid me to find your Bluecoats.
There they are.
- Get me the James boy.
- You want Jesse?
No, not Jesse.
I want the one that can shoot.
Frank!
- Hold your ground!
- Frank, up front!
Jesse, watch your back.
- Cannon or Gatling?
- Fire!
- Cannon!
- Cannons.
Where you been, buddy?
- What's goin' on?
- Well, nothin' really.
Every time I put my head up to hit
that Gatling, they try and shoot it off.
- So we got a plan?
- My plan of pissin' myself seems to be workin' fine!
Listen, I can hit those boys from here.
We just need a distraction.
A distraction?
Well, why the hell
didn't you just say so?
- He's smilin'.
- That's never a good thing.
Get that rider!
We're comin', Jesse!
Head out!
Take the hill!
Charge!
Fall back!
Go!
Go on, git. Git!
Go on! Go on!
- Distracting enough for you?
- They hardly even noticed you.
You're saying I could have done more to attract their attention.
- Such as?
- You could've worn one of those floppy women's Easter bonnets.
- That would've made an impression.
- I figure.
See, that's your problem, Frank.
By the time you finish
figurin' out stuff,
I'm already finished doin'it.
No, your problem is you're doin' stuff
before I'm finished figuring it out.
Goddamn, boy!
Wait till we get back to Missouri.
Tell all them little gals 'bout how little Jesse James
charged the whole Union army by hisself.
Cole, he keeps that up,
he's liable to outrank you soon.
Well, but I'll still be
better-looking, won't I?
Let's meet on that road over to the south.
See if we can't get those Yankees
old Jesse here scared off. Yaah!
- Ride with me, cousin.
- I could use the walk.
All right. Suit yourself. We'll have
some horses waitin' for you at the road.
All right, Rangers.
Let's ride!
Now, I would sound just stupid
saying something like that.
- Where you boys going?
- There's Yankees back there.
- Lots of'em.
- The war's over, son.
General Lee surrendered
esterday at Appomattox.
Yesterday.
Well, somebody better
go tell the damn Yankees.
- What do you reckon, cousin?
- Home.
Cole, we go home,
and we ride like hell to get there.
God help any fool who tries to come
between me and my farm again.
Now, that's the best damn plan
I heard all war.
Well, boys, let's ride!
Hello, Liberty, Missouri.
Let's go home,
back to our farms.
Plantin' corn,
harvestin' corn and eatin' corn.
- Corn gonna shoot at me?
- No.
- Then I love it.
- Let's go.
- We got problems.
- Got a garrison in town.
- We're in occupied territory, boys.
- Hands off your hip, Cole.
- You ain't scared, are you, Jesse?
- Pick your fights, cousin.
You taught me that.
- Jesus, mercy.
- That's Charlie Higgins.
- I'm cuttin' him down.
- Not now, Cole.
What in the hell
is wrong with you?
In case we have to kill these son of a
bitches, I don't want 'em to see us comin'.
I want to get back to the farm and make
sure Little Jim and the girls are okay.
Yeah, and stop by our spread after that
and tell our ma we're all right.
We'll go see Doc Mimms.
Excuse me, sir.
We're here for the doctor.
Jesse. Frank!
Zerelda?
Little Zee Mimms?
You were little Jesse James
when you left!
Yeah, but you got big.
I - I mean, Zee, you aged.
What I mean is, in a good way,
you got big and older.
- Frank, will you say something, please?
- No, you're doing just fine.
- Frank? Jesse?
- Daddy!
Where's Web?
He rode right into 'em,
screamin' like a banshee.
My little Web did that?
He jumped his horse clear over our heads
and killed a dozen Union soldiers...
before they knew
what hit 'em.
Took out the Gatling gun
and the cannon all by himself.
Saved all our lives, Doc.
None of the Liberty boys would
have come home if not for Web Mimms.
- God's honest truth.
- Web died fighting?
Web died a hero.
But still died.
Look, Doc, if there's
anything we can do for you,
we want to help.
- Start thinking about yourselves.
Don't end up
like Charlie Higgins.
They found out Charlie rode
with Quantrill's Raiders.
They arrested him, tried him by military
tribunal and hanged him this morning.
- I thought there was a general amnesty.
- For soldiers, yes.
But if you rode in one of the partisan
bands, they'll hang you for treason.
You boys are in more danger
'cause you've got a farm.
See, the railroad men
come through offering to buy up land.
Nobody sells, so the army starts hanging
men who own farms, for treason.
During the war, all we thought about
was coming home.
I swore I'd kill anybody who'd try
to get me off my farm again.
If I have to go to war with the
railroad to stay, that's fine by me.
Wait, wait. Let's think about this.
If we have a good story and we
stick to it, we should be all right.
What story are they
gonna believe, Frank?
Hmm, you were in the Confederate army
with General Hood's Texas army...
until, say, Sharpsburg, where you were
reassigned to General Stuart's cavalry...
until you surrendered in Tennessee.
That... just might work.
Yeah, that might just work.
Now, go on and see your ma.
She'll be glad to see her sons alive.
For her sake, stay that way.
Zee.
Thank you for everything.
- Especially that story that you told my father.
- Look, Zee...
I'm goin' to go cry now.
- That Zerelda turned into a hell of a woman, eh?
- Oh, yeah.
- "Big and older"?
- You can shut up now, Frank.
- You are a charmer.
- I swear to God I will shoot you in your sleep.
Next time try
"fat and haggard."
My boys? My boys!
My boys! My boys are alive!
Oh, God!
Praise God!
- You're alive!
- Not if you don't ease up a bit, Ma.
- Oh!
- Oh, Ma.
- Did you kill Yankees?
- A fair number, Ma.
- And did you say your prayers?
- Every night, Ma.
Good. Now, come on inside
and wash your hands for dinner.
- You look so good.
- You look great!
Howdy, boys.
Look at Jimmy Younger, all grown up.
- How ya doin'?
- All right.
- Your ma wouldn't let us leave until we ate somethin'.
- That was two hours ago.
- I don't see clean plates.
- Glad to see you being so nice to our Indian friend.
He's a good Christian,
and he killed Yankees.
And Jesus told me that made him
an all-right boy.
Well, she's still
talkin' to Jesus.
- What worries me is that Jesus is talkin' back.
- I heard that.
Come on, Frank.
You play me that eight.
- You ever notice Zerelda's eyes?
- Yeah.
Yeah, she got two
of'em, don't she?
- I think one of them's glass.
- Yeah, which one is that?
- Is that the right one or the left one?
- The brown one.
Cole, don't make me tell the whole town about
that time ou screwed that fella in Atlanta.
- Ooh.
- You talkin' to me?
- You mean that dance hall girl at Bunny's?
- Yeah.
Sadie was a beautiful woman.
Sadie was not a man.
- She had a nice mustache.
- I think she had more than a moustache.
- Well, she was European.
- Ah, all right.
I'll admit Sadie was a woman if you
just stop sayin' things about my Zee.
- "My Zee"?
- Your Zee?
- Yeah.
From women's eyes this doctrine
I derive: They sparkle still,
the right Promethean fire.
They are the books,
the arts, the academes...
that show, contain
and nourish all the world.
Well, I don't know what it is you
just said, but it sounded real nice.
That's Shakespeare.
Now, he's European.
Wanna write that down for me, Frank,
so I can say it to Zee?
- Yeah, I'll send you a telegram.
- Thanks, brother.
Thanks for the help, Cole.
You did plenty
over at our place.
You miss it, don't you?
What, the war?
Hell, no.
There are things
I miss about it, but...
- It was exciting.
- Yeah.
But it was a whole lot of killing,
and why should we miss that?
'Cause we were good at it.
Shoot, we were great at it.
Don't tell anybody
I said this.
I'm gonna have to kill you 'cause everybody
knows I'm the toughest man in town.
But you are one terrifying
son of a bitch with them guns.
Yeah, well.
Boys.
- Howdy, folks. How are you today?
- Howdy.
- Yeah, Easterners.
- We're just fine, thank you, sir.
I'm Rollin H. Parker,
personal emissary to Mr. Thaddeus Rains,
president of the Rock
Northern Railroad.
And this gentleman
is the famous Allan Pinkerton,
founder of the Secret Service and currently
under contract to Mr. Thaddeus Rains.
As you no doubt heard from your
neighbors, our railroad is moving west.
That makes sense 'cause, see,
east would put you underwater.
Moving west opened up the frontier
to folks such as yourselves.
It so happens that your acreage here is
located on the proposed right of way.
I am here
to get your signature...
on this land sale contract.
And I'm authorized
to pay you...
two dollars an acre.
- Two dollars?
- That's right.
That's the price approved by the Department
of Interior of the United States of America.
This land ain't for sale.
Ma'am, I can understand how you feel.
You've made a lovely home here,
but it really isn't up to me or you.
You familiar with the legal concept,
the right of eminent domain?
Yeah, I am.
What about it?
This land's about
to be condemned.
So I'm doing you folks a favor.
The price of two dollars an acre
is a one-time-only deal.
After today, the price goes down.
So if I were you, I would just sign the
contract, and we'll be on our way.
Good day, Mr. Parker.
You can tell Mr. Thaddeus Rains
to put this where the sun don't shine.
Shakespeare.
I don't think you understand.
You don't have a choice.
Ma'am, I think that you
should search your heart here...
and try to do the right thing.
Let me ask the Lord.
The Lord says we can
bury 'em out back in the orchard.
Nobody'll ever find 'em.
- Somebody's in a vengeful mood today.
- Let 'em go for today, Ma.
- We'll bury 'em out back next time.
- All right.
Now, ma'am...
You folks are making
a serious mistake here.
Nicely played.
Tell all the folks
what you told me, Frank.
I went to the courthouse to look at the
right-of-way documents for the rail bed.
The railroad doesn't
even need our land.
They're just using our land
on both sides for as far as they can.
Floor recognizes
Clell Miller.
They're sayin' if we don't sell,
we might end up with nothing.
- That's only if we don't stick together.
- Loni Packwood.
I say this is the last straw.
I came back from the war.
My farm was burned down.
My cows was dead.
And now my wife's run off
with my cousin Jeb.
That son of a bitch.
He took my dog.
Uh, Loni, about the railroad.
- He took my dog!
- They got Cole!
-  Daddy, he came to our house.
You all want to hear this.
They came up, they made the same offer
they made you folks.
Our little brother Jim
tried to chase 'em off.
One of the detectives hit him
in the head and knocked him out.
- Cole lost his temper.
- Oh, no.
- He lost his temper a little.
- How many of them did he kill?
- Two.
- Cole.
They said that because the detectives was
working for the Department of the Interior...
The army can hang him.
- Tomorrow.
- What do we do?
Nothin'.
You folks are gonna do nothin'.
You're gonna go home right now.
You too, Doc.
So you can swear on a Bible ou don't know
anything about what's gonna happen tomorrow.
- Boys...
- Doc!
Go home.
They ain't gonna hang
no more Liberty boys.
Go home.
Meeting's adjourned.
Go home, everybody.
Go home.
- I'm staying.
- Me too.
Loni, Clell.
- I couldn't lose him.
- Ah, Jim Younger!
- I told you to stay home!
- It's my fault they're gonna kill Cole. I want in.
It was a matter of time before they tried to
hang somebody else to scare off the other farmers.
- And you're too young.
- Too young?
I'm the same age you were
when you went to war.
Yeah, and the same age
Web was. No.
- You're wasting time.
- Zee, go home.
Who else was there when
they hanged the others?
You need to know how they do it,
which way they walk up,
what order they
do things in.
And if you mess up rescuing Cole
because you won't listen to a woman,
then damn you all.
All right.
Eight of us...
against a Union regiment
and Pinkerton detectives...
in the middle of Main Street
in broad daylight.
- He's smilin'.
- Is that bad?
Very.
Pinkerton, relax.
The army has everything well in hand.
Nothin' like a hanging to motivate
the population to relocate.
It's not my job to relax.
I've got men positioned
at every entrance to this square,
so no one will
ride in shooting.
And I've got a sharpshooter
up on that rooftop over there.
Just in case.
Be it known that Coleman Younger...
be found guilty of treasonable acts against
military law and the articles of war,
to be hanged this day
by the neck until dead.
May God have mercy on his soul.
Brilliant.
Hang him!
Pull it! Pull it!
Sir, are you all right?
Somebody get a doctor.
The bullet came out clean,
but he's lost an awful lot of blood.
He's gonna be fine,
right, Daddy?
Praying wouldn't hurt.
Who's that?
Stay here with him.
We're looking for a fugitive. We're
checking all the houses in the area.
Powell, out back.
McCall, check the first floor.
- I'm goin' up.
- Sir, who are you?
- Oh, sorry, ma'am.
- Well, I should hope so!
Go! Go.
Jesse, are you awake?
Jesse, is that your hand?
They're gone.
- What are you...
- I fooled them into thinking I was alone.
Let's hope the boy pulls through.
I think he's feeling better already.
Mr. Thaddeus Rains, sir. It's a pleasure
to have you join us in the field.
- Well, I'm pleased to be here.
- Really?
No, Parker, no. I'm really not
pleased to leave my boardroom,
come to this godforsaken piece of dirt
to discover why,
in the name of all that's holy, ou can't
seem to evict a few simple farmers...
from their pathetic
little mud holes...
so I can build the greatest railroad
the world has ever seen.
Well, I completely understand
our distress, sir.
What's going on?
Well, sir, two weeks ago we managed to
have the army hang one of the local farmers.
- That's good.
- No, unfortunately not, sir.
Uh, a group of local thugs managed
to rescue him from the gallows.
Not only did this inspire resistance
in the other farmers,
but the redoubtable Allan Pinkerton
was seriously injured in the incident.
Leaving you in charge of operations
until he should return.
A further impediment is that the army garrison
has been ordered to move on away from Liberty,
so we no longer have that particular stick
with which to threaten the farmers.
You see the army leaving,
you see the loss of a tool.
I see a power vacuum to be filled.
As we have the most power,
we may move with impunity.
I see, sir.
I'll get together four patrols of
our detectives for action tonight.
We'll teach these Podunks what happens when
they challenge the righteousness of progress.
Yes, sir.
- Jesse, you shouldn't be up.
- I've been on my back two weeks, Zee.
- I'm sick of it.
- You sick of my company?
No, 'course not, Zee.
Teasing you's
completely unfair.
What you do to me
is unfair.
- I shouldn't tease a hero.
- A what?
Everybody in the county knows
it was you who rescued Cole.
We're all so proud of you, Jesse.
Not a single farm's been
sold to the railroad since.
Oh, that's good.
But I wasn't the only person
risking my neck that day, so...
So you're saying that I should go
spend time with Cole Younger?
With Cole Younger?
No, I never said that.
You gonna stop loafin' around
with that young lady...
and get back to the farm?
- What do you think, Frank?
You get in the wagon!
Until Ma has you home so she can fuss over
you herself, she's gonna make me miserable.
- What do you say, sir?
- Go ahead. You're pretty much all healed up.
- Thank you, Doc.
- Of course.
Bye, Jesse.
Bye, Zee.
- You're lookin' a bit more spry.
- Shut up, Frank.
Doc? I was wonderin' if, uh,
later this evenin' I could come by.
You're always welcome here, Jess.
I know, but I was thinkin' maybe
I could come by and take Zee out.
You know, someplace near,
with other folk.
Near, you know, here, but... out.
That's fine by me, Jesse.
Oh, don't worry, sir. I'll make
sure they're properly chaperoned.
Well, that hadn't even
occurred to me, Frank.
I am deeply in your debt.
Well, you are
very welcome, sir.
The army's leaving town, so Cole can stop
hidin' up in the woods and get back to his farm.
We're all gonna meet
at the Younger place for a shindig.
Hey, you leave them alone.
Leave 'em alone.
- Cole.
- Clell.
- How are ya?
- Hey, John.
- Good to see you. Thanks for comin'.
- Welcome back.
- How are ya?
- Hey, Cole Younger.
Who's seen Loni Packwood,
how he's dressed? Look at that!
Tom.
Come here, huh?
Thank you.
You behave yourselves, you hear?
- Liberty's favorite son. Come here!
- Hi, Cole.
I'll never forget what you did, cousin.
You know it?
- Zee, I'm pleased you came.
- Why, thank you, Bob.
I'm especially pleased
you came with Jesse,
seeing as right now there's a gaggle
of girls hopin' to dance with Jesse...
who are just gonna have to settle
with the many charms of Bob Younger.
- Bob, you have no shame.
- Not yet, but I'm hopin'.
- Come on, let's dance.
- Okay.
I used to come to this rock
all the time when I was a kid.
Just imaginin' what my life
would be like when I got older.
You didn't want a farm?
I was thinkin' more along the lines
of being a river pirate.
- A river pirate?
- Yeah. Argh, hand over our jewels, missy!
Well, thank God
ou grew out of that.
You did grow out of that,
didn't you?
Mostly, yeah. It would be
an all-right life for a bachelor.
A - Are you plannin' on bein'
a bachelor your whole life, JesseJames?
Not if I find the right girl.
What's this right girl like?
What's she like?
She's, uh, she's smart.
She's funny.
She's bossy.
She always makes me think
she's at least two steps ahead of me.
Where will you find such a girl?
From this doctrine...
Damn.
From women's eyes these doctrine...
this doctrine I derive:
They sparkle...
still, like...
tiny... sparkling rocks.
- Darn it.
- Sparkling rocks?
Yeah, little ones, see.
Is this one of Frank's Shakespeare poems
you're trying to duote?
Yes, it is.
Were, um... Were you planning on
kissing me when you finished quoting?
Been planning on kissing you
for a very long time.
Bastards!
Come back here and face me!
- Jimmy!
- Cole, what'd they do?
Let's get back. We need some
water. Let's get some buckets.
- Get buckets!
- Water!
Come on.
- Frank.
- It's the Pinkertons. It's the railroad.
Then Ma... Ma!
Come on!
Thank God.
Ma!
Ma! Ma!
Hang on, Ma.
We gotta get you to Doc Mimms.
You boys... take care...
take care of each other.
Ma, Doc Mimms...
Well, look at that.
The good Lord's a bit shorter
than I reckoned.
Ma.
I think we can move on,
rebuild,
make a decent life
someplace else.
I don't care.
I didn't think you would.
Our place, Clell Miller's,
Sammy Johnston, the Creeders, Will Hite.
The sheriff said it was
a gang of drunk Kansas boys.
I say we ride into town and kill us
some Pinkertons and railroad men.
No. This isn't a feud. This is war.
They've got more men than we do.
So what do we do,
General Lee?
We do what we did
in the war.
We harass their supply lines. We try and
kill the railroad's men, they won't care.
But if we take away
their money and supplies...
- Exactly.
- That's a good plan, Jesse.
I'll get us a few more men.
Comanche Tom'll ride with us.
- What do we hit first?
- I know a gal down at the bank.
See if she can't get me a list of towns
where the railroad's keepin' its money.
I'm so sorry, Jesse.
Me and Frank have to
go away for a while.
But you and I,
we've started something, you know?
I don't know what'll happen
if you do this.
- Neither do I.
- Just let the law...
Laws don't touch men like
Thaddeus Rains. Only justice does.
Whose justice,
ours or God's?
When will you stop?
When I send them
to their graves.
Thank you very much.
Excuse me, ladies and gentlemen.
I have bad news.
- The railroad payroll has been stolen.
- What are you talking about?
The railroad's money
is right there in that safe.
That safe?
Excuse me, sir.
- The bank's closed today.
- What?
- Bank holiday.
- There ain't no dadburned bank holiday!
- Get out of my way! Get out of my way!
- Ow! Hey!
This is outrageous.
Who are you people?
The James Gang.
- The James Gang?
- Yeah.
How 'bout the, uh,
James-Younger Gang?
The James-Younger Gang.
- I'll whop you real good now if you don't get out...
- The bank is closed.
- I gotta get through.
- Ow! Stop!
- I'll show you "ow"!
Excuse me, sir?
It's a bank holiday.
Ain't no dadburned bank holiday!
What are you talkin' about?
- Mister! What the hell are you doing, mister?
- Go on!
- Sir, the safe.
- Ma'am.
- Do me a favor. Turn around, cover your eyes.
- Why?
I'm gonna shoot this man. I don't
think you want to see it. Thank you.
Hey. The safe.
Now!
- It ain't no bank holiday!
- It's a bank holiday!
- It ain't!
- You're right, sir.
Well, then why can't I
go in there?
On account of that we're,
uh, robbing it.
Oh, why didn't you just
say so in the first place?
- It's a secret.
- Oh!
Fine.
Uh, I'll just wait over here.
I'd appreciate that.
Go on!
Get outta here.
- What the...
- What is it?
Old Man Tucker is just sittin' there
quiet outside the bank.
- So?
- So when have you ever known Old Man Tucker...
not to be yellin'
at everybody?
- How'd it go in there?
- Fine. How'd it go out here?
I think we should talk.
Sir, you can do this
the smart way or the stupid way.
Only one way ends
with you still breathin'.
Just 'cause we're
robbin' a bank,
there's no reason not to be civil about it.
Where the hell were you?
I had you covered.
- I got 5,000.
- I got three.
Eight thousand dollars!
That's a thousand apiece!
Our luck
is finally changing.
What do we do with these?
These are the property rights to the farms
that the bank was holdin' for the railroad.
You better pass them over here
before somethin' happens to 'em.
Whoops.
All right.
Settle down.
Not all this money's ours.
Uh, well, no, Jesse,
it was the bank's.
See, that's why we had to go
to all the trouble of stealing it.
We oughta take some of this money,
give it to our neighbors in Liberty.
- Lot of people hurtin' there.
- None of them risked their necks for this.
Let's think about this.
We create goodwill with the folk
hereabout, make it easier to dodge the law.
- Frank's being smart about this.
- No, Jesse.
Just because he reads them books and knows
all them big words don't make him smart.
- Uh, yeah, it does.
- No, it don't, Bob. Stay out of this.
- I think Jesse's got a good idea.
- Jim?
Who put you in charge
of this gang, Jesse, huh?
- I did a mighty fine job leadin' us durin' the war.
- You did, Cole.
I seem to remember
cuttin' a noose from your neck.
That's why you both
lead the gang.
Two of you entered
that bank together, right?
Two heads are better than one.
All Jesse's doin'
is makin' a suggestion.
So we're waitin'to hear what
you think of that suggestion, Cole,
as the other leader of the gang.
That's fine.
- What's that?
- I reckon it's a smart thing to do.
- Cole!
- Hey, that's it.
We decide somethin',
that's it.
Now, we're in this
for the long haul,
and this plan
of me and Jesse's...
smart, help us,
give us places to hide.
We don't have to worry about a farmer
with a shotgun shootin'us in our sleep.
We got to think...
What's that word, Frank?
"Strategically."
Yeah. Thank you.
Strategically.
- 'Cause this is a war.
- This ain't no war.
What's that?
Nobody paid me no thousand dollars
to fight in a war.
- One down.
- Damn it, Tom. You cheatin' again?
- I'm broke again.
- Next up, Thaxton Switch.
- Yeah, see, that ain't a bank, Jesse.
- It's better.
It's a construction depot, so it'll have
the strongbox, some ammo, explosives.
We can take those. That way we
can do a bigger job next time.
And it's guarded
by Pinkerton detectives.
And I do so want to kill me
some Pinkerton detectives.
Boys!
We're famous.
What's this?
"The Fidelity Bank was robbed on Tuesday
by a gang of 20 heavily armed men."
Twenty?
What are the odds?
Another gang robbin' the same
bank on the same day as us.
"The outlaws, calling themselves
the James-Younger Gang,
"shot their way out of town,
wounding the sheriff...
"and three other townsfolk.
The bank officials estimate
the loss of $50,000."
Fifty thousand dollars?
More like fifty thousand pesos.
"U.S. District marshal called this the first
daylight bank robbery in American history."
- Here's to history.
- I'll drink to that.
We made history?
That is something to be proud of.
Yeah, the rest of that's
a bunch of horseshit.
That means next time we're gonna have
to set the record straight ourselves.
Line 'em up!
- Barkeep!
- Whiskey!
They exchanged fire with the
Pinkerton guards, wounding several.
Then they raided the payroll office
and blew the track.
How much did they get
from the safe?
Thirty-five thousand, sir,
in coins and currency,
not to mention the added delay
of miles of destroyed track.
I'll kill 'em
for blowing up my railway.
To be precise, sir,
they didn't actually blow the track.
Then who did?
- Whoa!
- We did.
I mean, our men... did.
Our workers planted the dynamite,
but they were under duress.
Pinkerton, what is going on here?
My professional opinion...
is that you've managed to piss off
the wrong bunch of farm boys this time.
- They had to be dealt with.
- By burning down their homes?
You wouldn't have done that?
Oh, I'd have done that, all right, but
I'd have made sure I killed 'em all first.
I want them arrested
and hanged.
Do you think a jury in these parts
would convict one of their own?
Uh-uh. I doubt it.
We're beginning a very interesting
game here, Mr. Rains.
This is no game.
Well, I'm afraid our adversaries...
don't agree.
"Rock Island Pacific
Railroad Depot was robbed...
"just outside of St. Louis, Missouri.
"The brave and daring
James-Younger Gang...
"was heavily outnumbered
by Pinkerton detectives,
but the city lawmen were no match
for the guns of the West."
Fine piece of writin'.
"The gang destroyed
the Thaxton Switch construction,
"meaning that, for a few months,
honest farmers will be able to sleep...
without fearing the railroad
is coming to steal their land."
Who wrote this? I'll see 'em
hanged every Tuesday for a month.
Oh, that's the best part.
"Foregoing article was sent to this
newspaper, was reputedly written...
by the outlaw
JesseJames himself."
- Hey, look at that!
- What is it?
"Better."
"Slow... down."
"Dynamite...
ahead."
"Too late."
"You're dead!"
Ohh!
Whoo! Yes, sir!
That was a fine
piece of driving.
Damn!
Thank you. Four more payments, and
you'll be caught up on the mortgage.
You have to look carefully at these Yankee
two-dollar bills. I've gotten funny ones lately.
- Good day to you, sir.
- Good afternoon, sir. Could you change this for me?
- Certainly, sir.
- Thank you.
Sir, I'm sorry, but this bill is counterfeit.
I don't think so.
I'm gonna have to see the rest
of your money so I can compare.
It's a scientific method.
I hear it's all the rage.
Yes, you... you can compare
all of them, Mr...
- James.
- Jesse James?
Yes, sir. It's a terrible sketch.
- That's all I have, sir.
- Why, thank you. It's been a pleasure.
- Yes, sir.
- Take care now, you hear?
- Good-bye, sir. Have a good day.
- Good-bye.
Pinkerton, why can't you catch
these outlaws?
It's early in the game yet, sir.
Jesse James and I are just
learning each other's moves,
feeling out each other's patterns.
Oh. Well, I'm losing millions
of dollars and months of time...
while you play chess with these farmers.
- Hardly farmers, sir.
Each one of these men has four years of
bloody fightin' experience behind 'em.
They are disciplined
and have a charismatic leader.
If I were to design
the perfect outlaw band,
this is the gang I'd create.
So what can you tell me?
It's going to be
a long winter.
Let's go!
Take this road.
Come on!
Come on, boys!
Go, go!
Whew! Never thought
that posse was gonna give up.
Yeah, they were
admirably persistent.
That's the longest chase
we've had.
- Jesse, we've gotta have a word.
- Sure, cousin.
All the newspapers are calling
this bunch the James-Younger Gang.
- Right?
- Yeah.
Why the hell aren't we
the Younger-James Gang?
We got three Younger brothers
and two James brothers.
I like the sound
of the James-Younger Gang.
Jim, I'll beat the piss out of
you right now. Stay out of this.
Jimmy's got a point, Cole.
The "Younger-James Gang" is confusing.
- How's that, Bob?
- Well.
Say we burst into a bank, and we yell,
"We're the Younger-James Gang!"
People are gonna be thinkin',
"The younger James gang?
"Is there an older James gang?
- Hey!
How come we never heard
of the older James gang?"
So people tryin' to figure that out
instead of raisin' their arms.
- Can't argue with that, Cole.
- Do we even have the same mama? Huh?
Do we? Is anybody hearin' me? Huh?
See, I got a little idea.
If I kill you, then I kill Jim,
I'm gonna have no arguments.
Pinkerton? It's been eight months.
I see holdups and I see robberies.
I don't see men
on the end of nooses.
Most of these James Gang's encounters
have been with local law enforcement.
Quite frankly are no match
for this gang's cunning.
- What about your detectives?
- Listen, you!
Shut up.
Now...
I have to hunt this man.
I have to get inside
this man's mind.
I have to anticipate him.
- And that takes time.
- Time, time, time.
I can't believe this.
Would you believe there are
certain towns in Missouri...
where the James Gang
walks openly in the street...
as heroes?
- Now, how can that be?
Because they are charitable.
- They give money to churches, to farmers.
- Was blind
But now I see
- They gave the sharecroppers of Maddox so much money,
they even built a school.
- That's my money.
- Well, sir, we should burn that school to the ground.
That's the way to win'em
back to our side.
Pinkerton, hundreds of men have
lost their lives to build this railroad,
but they did their jobs.
Now, this...
this Jesse James, that's your job.
Do your job.
Then you let me do my job
as I see fit,
without interference.
- What can you tell me?
- It's going to be a long spring.
If people would just hand over
their money and not shoot at us,
there'd be a lot less killing.
- What's that?
- It's my lucky rabbit's foot.
Took it off
that dead fellow over there.
- I don't think that one's working, Loni.
- What?
- Jesse James!
- Can I have your autograph?
Take us to the West.
Lane, Grogan, you take this.
You take these towns.
You remind me of...
Here, write this.
I'm not writing this.
Your blue-green eyes remind me of...
- Remind me of that land in the sky.
- The land in the sky.
That "even here." You might want to
change that to, uh, "I thought of you."
Ah, look, just write
the whole thing yourself. I...
Okay, sir, I think we know
how this is gonna go.
One false move and I'll blow your head off!
- Bob?
- You heard me, Jesse!
You know how crazy I get!
Crazy!
Bob.
- We got a problem, little brother?
- Frankly, yeah.
- I'm feelin' a little... left out.
- Oh!
- This is about the wanted posters, isn't it?
- Yeah.
Obviously someone's not standin' out
in people's minds at the robberies.
Gents, we're in the middle
of somethin' here.
- Yeah, Bob's upset.
- The posters?
- Yeah.
- Don't say "yeah" in that tone of voice!
- This is important!
- Okay.
Pardon the delay, folks,
but we had to get...
"Mad" Bob Younger under control.
Yeah. Bob here'll kill a man
for sneezin'. He's the best shot in the gang.
Better than you, Jesse?
Bob Younger...
taught me how to shoot.
Now...
how 'bout we get back
to the robbery?
Of course.
That means now, mister!
Now.
- Come on. Talk to me.
- Oh!
Talk to me one more time.
Pretty please.
- Yeah!
- Damn, Loni, you're lucky.
Luckiest man in the West...
now that I'm ridin' with Jesse James.
- You okay, Jesse?
- Drinkin' whiskey, Jim?
You're too young
to be drinkin' whiskey.
Not too young to shoot a man,
not too young to drink whiskey.
Jim, you, uh,
been with a girl yet?
Tonight?
Why, I was just gettin' ready
to go turn on that Younger charm.
- Well, not exactly.
- You been with a girl ever?
Hell, yeah,
I've been with a girl!
Look, I didn't want to get
one of them paid ladies.
- You know what I mean?
- I think so.
I mean, you, Frank, Cole, even Bob,
you get all the girls 'cause
you're good-lookin' and famous.
They just look at me
like I'm your baby brother.
- Don't tell nobody.
- I swear. Not a word.
- You okay?
- Tell you what...
Uh! I can't
drink good neither.
- I'm gonna go outside and throw up.
- You do that. Hurry.
Hey, Loni.
Oh, yeah!
Let's go, sugar britches.
Just call me "Lucky" Loni Packwood.
The new route for the railroad
is complete, sir.
- Parker?
- Yes, sir?
- What's that?
- That, sir?
Jenkins will explain that.
- Sir!
- Jenkins.
Yes, well, uh, we have done a financial study...
of the construction costs projecting...
- Jenkins!
It's... cheaper to go around
Jesse James, sir.
Even with the detours
and the extra track,
it's - it's just... cheaper.
So... you are telling me...
that Jesse James has won?
Oh, no.
No, no, no.
You see, every three months
the James Gang circles back...
to the vicinity
of Liberty, Missouri,
and they always pull a job before they return.
- So?
So there's only four banks within
that travel radius they've not robbed.
Could you put men
at all four?
I don't have to.
I've a much better tool at my disposal
for narrowing it down to one bank.
- What's that?
- An intense hatred of you.
Jesse.
Things a fella's gotta do to get
a little respect around here.
- Finally. You deserve it, Bob. It's about time.
- Thank you.
Listen, Jesse, um...
we got a problem.
It's Cole.
Ah, he's been
full of vinegar lately.
- He's plannin' a job.
- He's what?
- Look, he's my brother, and I don't wanna start trouble.
- Tell me.
- Cole, are you sure?
- Tell you what, boys.
- This is gonna be the biggest score yet.
- What will be?
Hyperion Bank.
Two days ride from Liberty.
- Got $ 100,000 in railroad money just sittin' there.
- That's in the paper, huh?
- Don't sound right.
- If you read about it first, you'd have no problems.
What are you saying, Cole?
Jesse, I've robbed
just as many banks as you have.
I know this town, I know this bank,
and I say it's an easy job.
- I think you're forgettin' who's in charge.
- Jesse.
You're in charge? Huh?
We ain't partners no more, Jesse?
Let me get this straight. You tell
Cole Younger when and where to ride?
- Cole, he didn't mean that.
- You're takin' sides against me now, Frank?
- No.
- So bein' with me is bein' against you?
We don't wanna do that.
No.
None of us poor idiots wanna
go up against Jesse James.
Greatest outlaw
who ever lived.
That's what it says
in the paper.
Weren't for you, this gang wouldn't be
able to find a goat's ass with a stick.
You have gotten mighty full
of yourself lately, Jesse.
You think so?
You all do?
Frank?
The one time one of us
comes up with an idea...
- A bad idea.
- Hey, I got us through the war all right.
- And nearly got hanged in peacetime.
- Jeez!
Cole!
Boys, we don't want this!
- I'm the better soldier, Jesse!
- And I'm the better outlaw!
You both hate the railroad!
That's all that matters!
You do this job, and Thaddeus Rains
will never come west again!
- What are you talkin' about?
- It's his money.
He's paying the payroll
out of his own fortune.
You do want to hurt Thaddeus Rains,
don't you, Jesse?
- Come on, boys! Put your guns down.
- I still don't like it.
- Then let me run the show, General Lee!
- Jesse.
Jesse!
You want it?
All right.
We hit this bank.
You'll be smilin' once you got
that money in your pocket, cousin.
Cole Younger's gonna make
everyone rich!
Hands in the air!
- We're robbin' this bank.
- Move over there!
Everybody does what they're told,
nobody's gonna die. Hands up!
Oh, no.
- Which one should I shoot first?
- None of 'em.
Jesse!
You all right?
Head for the end
of the street!
- Look!
- Damn!
Son of a bitch!
Move! Go on!
- Another dozen out back.
- They gonna rush us?
Nah, they're just insurance
in case we run.
Inside!
For God's sakes, move!
Get in!
Any ideas, little brother?
Oh, Lord.
- Oh, Lord.
Oh, shit! Let's git!
Fire! Come on!
Come on!
Look out!
Damn!
Let's go, boys!
Come on!
Let's go.
Come on, boys!
Come on!
Jimmy!
- Damn!
- Look what they did to the town.
Easy, easy. Easy. It'll be okay.
Okay.
You're gonna rest here now.
- Bob, get some bandages.
- How's 'bout some whiskey?
- Okay.
- Too young for whiskey.
- I think this time we'll make an exception, Jim.
- Little brother... sorry.
All right, Jim?
I'm sorry.
It was the best time
of my life.
I was famous, ya know?
Yeah.
Little brother.
- He was just a kid.
- He was old enough.
He was a boy riding with the most
famous outlaws in the West, Frank.
How was he supposed
to say no to that?
Railroad burned him out too.
You couldn't have stopped him.
You're a piss-poor liar
for the smartest man I know.
A war against
the railroad.
What the hell
was I thinkin'?
Well, I'm sure it seemed
like a good idea at the time.
- I'm out.
- You're out?
We ride for a year and our blood gets
spilled and you're just gonna quit?
Who's next, Cole?
You? Me? Bob?
Can't exactly go back
to our lives, Jesse.
I ain't tellin'you what to do, Clell. You want
to keep ridin' with Cole, that's fine by me.
Frank?
Well... go on.
Get the hell out of here then.
Don't come back when you find
you can't farm with a six-gun.
Jesse.
What are you thinkin'?
There are lawmen and bounty hunters
all over this county.
I had to see you.
I'm gettin' married.
I don't understand.
Well, she's the most
wonderful woman in the world.
I can't stop thinkin'
about her.
Zee, look, I've quit
my outlaw ways.
Come live in my home...
and in my heart.
Be my wife.
Is that a yes?
I never would've
imagined us in a place like this.
That's why I picked it.
We can start a whole new life here, Zee.
Do you think you'll be happy here in Florida,
Mr. James, without all that excitement?
I've got you.
You keep me busy.
I figure we can go up to the hotel,
get checked in.
And then I wanna do somethin' I've been
thinkin' about doin' for a long, long time.
Now wait a minute! There are certain things
that have to wait until after the wedding.
Driver, change of plans.
Could you take us to
the nearest church, please?
"Jesse Woodson James."
Jesse James.
The Jesse James?
I could've lied, I guess,
but I want this marriage to be legal.
And I want you to know that I'm trying to start
a new life here, so I'm depending on your...
- Discretion.
- Sir, I'm a man of the cloth...
- Well, thank you.
Who, ah, needs to repair
a leaky church roof.
Of course.
Now... let's have a drink.
In the church?
Communion!
- Have a good day, now.
- Hands in the air! This is a robbery!
Move! Move!
The safe! Now!
Of course. Of course.
- Sir?
- What?
Where's Jesse James?
This here's the Younger Gang. Ya
understand? The Younger Gang!
- But the Youngers ride with Jesse James.
- Hey! You wanna die?
No.
Did ride. No more.
Ya understand?
- The safe! Now! All right?
- All right, all right!
You know, Jesse James never
went around yellin' at folks.
Ah, Cole, this is the best score yet!
It's still takin' too long.
People used to snap to.
Yeah, well, that was because of...
the reputation the gang had.
As long as people think Jesse is still ridin',
we're not gonna get the respect we deserve.
Cole, we're outlaws. Not exactly the most
respectable job, if you know what I mean.
Bob, leave me alone, all right?
Go on.
- Hmm.
- "Hmm" what?
"For the life of the James Gang wasn't
all robbing and shooting and killing.
"These young Missouri bucks
had a taste for the ladies,
especially the handsome and charismatic Jesse James."
- Beg your pardon?
"Blazing Guns of the West.
True stories of Jesse James."
- Only a dime in the hotel lobby.
- Let me see that.
I'm not finished.
"When he sauntered into a saloon, his
spurs janglin' and his pockets full of gold,
the ladies flocked around him
like flies to a candied apple."
As I said, "Hmm."
Now, sweetie...
'all wouldn't go believin' one of them
silly dime novels, would ya?
Swimming.
Swimming is good.
Don't turn around.
What?
If you don't see it,
then it's not real.
Jesse James!
You're under arrest!
They arrested Jesse!
- What have you done?
- What's that, Bob?
- What have you done, Cole?
- I ain't done nothin', Bob.
Swear.
Swear on Jimmy's grave.
Bob... you know Cole
would never do such a thing.
He and Jesse are
best friends... cousins...
blood brothers.
Bob.
Sorry, Cole.
- We're moving you tomorrow.
- But I like the presidential suite.
You'll get a similar room.
- But the hotel's in Washington, D.C.
- Nice.
You're not gonna get a fair trial here in
front of a jury of Jesse James sympathizers.
But I'll get a fair trial with a jury
bought off by Thaddeus Rains?
That's the idea.
- Did you order our houses burned down?
- Not that day.
I'm guilty of many things, but...
that - that was Mr. Thaddeus Rains
and Parker that day.
- This was you, by the way.
- You almost ended my career before it began.
Pity.
We're gonna hang you,
you know.
Yeah, I figured.
Was it worth it?
- I should've just killed Thaddeus Rains.
- That's what I'd have done.
I'm not hanged yet.
You cocky little bastard!
Oh, you'll miss me.
No.
I'll hang you.
But I might miss you a little bit.
About face!
March. March.
Come on, you!
So, this is he.
- I remember you.
- You're Parker. I remember you too.
- You killed my ma.
- How did you know?
Not such a menace now,
is he, Pinkerton?
If that's the way you feel,
I could always take off his irons.
You stole thousands,
cost me tens of millions of dollars,
months of delays
in construction.
I wish I could hang you
every single morning for a century.
Oh, you like that?
Solid gold.
My father had it made.
When he started this railroad,
he gave it to me.
I'll give it to my son when he takes over
the company, and he'll give it to his son.
The right sort of men will always
run this country, Jesse James.
Not your sort.
You'll always suffer.
And you haven't changed anything.
I made you think twice about burnin'
folks' homes down, now, didn't I?
We'll speak again
in Washington.
Oh, you're comin'
on the same train?
Well, I'll tell you what.
I'm gonna have to pay you a visit.
- Big words.
- It's a promise.
Get him on board.
Open up!
- Hook him up.
- Come with me, boy.
Take him back.
Now your guns.
I don't like it.
We can handle him.
In the ten seconds we have been in this
car, I've seen you get close enough...
for Jesse James to grab your guns
at least three times!
And believe me, if he lays a finger
on one of your guns,
you are all... and I mean all... dead men.
He's chained up.
They'll put that on your tombstone.
Your guns.
Gimme two good cards.
Everybody ante up.
- Mm-hmm.
- Yeah.
- Yep.
Hey, stupid!
Yeah, you.
Glad to see you know your name,
a dumb shit!
- What are you saying, boy?
- I think I recognize you.
- How?
- I think I saw you leavin' by the front door...
just as I was
comin' in the back.
You shut up now, boy!
Yeah, your wife said
you did that to her too.
Will this shut you up?
You know, I could do
this without the gun.
It just makes things easier.
There he is!
What the hell is that?
Vengeance. Outside.
Get up on the roof!
Go, go, go!
You stay put, gentlemen.
Where is that varmint?
Hold it!
- Nice shot!
- Thank you.
Go get my husband.
There's only four of'em!
Move, you fools!
Move!
Hands up!
Come on! Quickly!
This way.
Do it.
That was for my ma.
- This is for everybody else.
- He's too important, James! They'll set the army on ya!
You and your wife.
That is a nice watch you got there.
Hand it over.
If I can get you today,
you damn sure know I can kill you
anytime I want, now that I'm free.
You sleep on that
for the next 20 years.
Give it to me.
Get your hands up! Now!
Tennessee. The railroad has
no business in Tennessee.
Therefore I have no interest
in the state of Tennessee.
Thank you.
I'd just as soon kill you,
Jesse James,
but chasin' ya takes up
too much of my time.
Fair enough.
Jesse James.
Come on! Let's ride!
Go! Let's go!
- You get arrested again, I'll kill you.
- Yes, ma'am.
- I can't believe that I had to blow up a train for you.
- You are a hell of a woman.
- Don't swear!
- Yes, ma'am.
- I missed you, cousin.
- I missed you too, cousin.
You know, uh...
You know, when you got caught, some people
thought maybe I had somethin' to do with it.
- The thought never crossed my mind.
- Good.
Things changed when you
quit the gang, Jesse.
For example, I'm the one
who now says, "Let's ride."
- He ain't bad at it.
- Yeah?
- It's tougher than it looks.
- Yeah!
- Where'd you get these riders?
- We didn't. Zerelda did.
- Turns out your wife makes a hell of an outlaw.
- What's the plan, Jesse?
- Well, Bob, I think my wife and I are gonna go and buy a farm.
- A farm?
- Down in Tennessee.
- All right.
You, uh... You wanna maybe ride with the
Younger Gang for a while before you do that?
Bye, boys.
Tom.
- Tennessee, huh?
- Yeah, I think so.
- I'll meet you there in a couple of weeks.
- I'll see you soon.
And, uh... thanks for that
distraction back there.
Hell, they hardly
even noticed us.
- Mrs. James?
- Shall we?
Shall we, indeed. Frank.
Rangers.
- Tennessee?
- I'll explain on the way.
All right, boys.
Let's ride!
- When were you plannin' on tellin' me?
- I just did.
- Only because I asked?
- Damn! Am I ever gonna win with you?
Don't change the subject.